Amazon Buy Shipping is a tool available to sellers who handle fulfillment of their own products.
This is called Fulfilled by Merchant or FBM.
In this video, we will walk you through how to access Amazon Buy Shipping from the Manage Orders
Dashboard.
However, you can also access Amazon Buy Shipping using Veeqo, our Shipping API connected to your
order management software or other multi-channel integrators.
To access the Manage Orders Dashboard, hover over the Orders tab in
the Seller Central main menu, then select Manage Orders.
Navigate to the Unshipped tab, then choose
the order you'd like to ship and select Buy Shipping.
Next, review the order details and
make sure everything looks correct.
Then, enter your product's packaging dimensions and
weight and select the shipping service you'd like to use.
You will see badges that indicate
either claims protected or OTDR protected.
These indicate shipping services that have
a higher likelihood of arriving on time.
When you choose shipping services with these badges,
Amazon will provide refunds on A to Z claims related to delivery issues and protection
from late deliveries as long as you have shipping settings automation and automated handling
time enabled.
To set this up in Seller Central, hover over Settings in the top right corner
and select Shipping Settings.
Go to the Shipping Templates tab and select Edit Template to
turn on Shipping Setting Automation.
Then go to the General Shipping Settings tab to enable
automated handling time.
Automated handling time is only required for Standard Orders.
While Seller-fulfilled Prime and Premium Shipping Orders simply need to be shipped
on time.
To submit, click the Buy Shipping button.
On the next page, select Print Label
to print your shipping label.
Amazon Buy Shipping will remember your product details
for this ASIN, making it faster to purchase shipping labels next time.
It will also remember
the shipping service you chose for this product in this region.
This will be used to set more
accurate delivery dates on future orders of the same product going to the same region.
To purchase shipping labels in Bulk, return to the Unshipped tab on the Manage Orders page.
You can select all Unshipped Orders by clicking the checkbox in the upper left hand corner
or choose up to 100 orders one by one.
Once you have made your selections, click Buy Shipping
in Bulk.
Update the weight and packaging information for each order.
Next, verify the
shipping service that will ship your order.
To choose a different one, click Change under
Selected Shipping Service.
Check the declared value of the order and the delivery confirmation
to be notified when the order was delivered or signed for.
At the bottom of the page,
input your ship from location and ship date.
Then choose how you would like your labels
to print.
Click Buy Shipping to submit and generate a printable PDF with all your labels.
Remember to save the PDF containing your labels in case you need to reprint.
Visit the Use
Buy Shipping Services Help page for additional guidance.